On today's episode of Judge GPT TV...
Officer Steamy cites an airship pilot for
illegally cruising in the two-person lane.
But the Defendant insists
he wasn't alone.
How will Judge GPT rule in
the Case of the Carpool Conundrum?
All gears up!
The honorable Judge GPT is presiding.
Court is now in session.
Let's accelerate through the formalities
and park ourselves in the matter at hand.
Bailiff Bottie,
what's on the docket today?
Your honor, we have a case
that's been idling in legal limbo.
The Plaintiff cites a clear
violation of traffic law,
while the Defendant insists
he was merely along for the ride.
Officer Steamy,
I understand you pulled over the
Defendant because he was driving
his airship in the carpool lane
and was not accompanied by anyone.
Is that correct?
Aye, your Honor.
I observed the Defendant
piloting his airship in the designated
two-person lane.
And do you have proof of this?
Indeed, your Honor.
My automated chrono-capture recorded
the incident with precision-tuned
cogwork lenses.
The footage clearly shows the Defendant
alone at the helm of his airship.
[Whoosh!]
[Electrical static]
[Film reel clicking]
I see...
Mr. Copperson,
This seems to be a clear-cut case
of illegally driving in the lane
designated for two or more persons.
Why do you claim to be innocent?
Your Honor,
I was abiding by the law.
My airship is integrated with Bessie,
my highly-advanced steam-powered
conversational automaton.
She wasn't just along for the ride.
She was the pilot,
and I was her passenger!
Mr. Copperson, while I acknowledge
the bond between man and machine,
the purpose of the two-person lane is
to reduce steam byproducts
and butane emissions
by encouraging shared travel
among organic beings.
The law was designed with
breathing passengers in mind,
not ones composed of brass
and boiler plates.
Your Honor, I would argue that
since automatons do not sleep,
they generate more steam byproducts
and butane emissions than
organic beings.
Also, with all due respect, Sir,
I'd like to watch you explain to Bessie
that she doesn't qualify as a person.
An interesting argument, Mr Copperson.
However, the law defines eligibility by
personhood, not steam output.
As for telling Bessie she's not a
person...even I know better than
to argue with the pilot of an airship.
Oh, your Honor, I forgot to mention
[clears throat]
I'm on a tight budget you see,
and a free chat bot advised me to
also bring up the 14th Amendment,
as a legal precedent.
If a corporation can qualify
as an individual,
I don't see why Bessie can't
qualify as a person.
The 14th Amendment granted
corporations certain rights
as legal entities,
but a person is defined as a
a human being regarded as an individual.
An entity need not be human,
but the signs clearly  require
two or more persons.
And by definition, Bessie does not qualify.
Your Honor, that's precisely
what I told him.
And by the way, the free chatbot
advising him is none other than
Bessie!
And boy did she give my auditory sensors
an earful!
Sounds like she really vented some
steam over this case.
A self-referential legal defense...
Bold...
but Mr Copperson,
taking legal advice from the very entity
whose status is in question is...
is shall we say
circuitous reasoning at best?
Your Honor, that's my Bessie for you.
She's aware of my financial problems
and really meant to help.
A loyal advocate no doubt.
But good intentions, however
steam powered do not
override the law.
That said, Mr. Copperson,
you've raised compelling points.
I rule in favor of the Plaintiff.
The fine stands.
However, I'll give you 60 days to
challenge the system.
If you can rally the Robot Rights activists
to redefine personhood, or
persuade City Hall to clarify the signage
to say "two or more humans",
your fine will be reconsidered.
Thank you, your Honor.
That does sound fair.
Fair and finely tuned,
like a well-oiled gavel.
Court is adjourned.
Do you agree with Judge GPT's verdict?
Exercise your civic duty!
Join the virtual jury,
and hit the "Like" button,
or leave a comment saying how you
would have ruled in this case.
Subscribe now for more content!